[upbeat rock music]
[欢快的摇滚音乐]
- Look at them up there.
看他们在上面。
Thinking they're better than everyone else.
以为自己比所有人都强。
- 'Cause they are. - Totally.
- 因为他们就是。
- Way better.
强多了。
- Hey, the coolest kids get the coolest hangout:
嘿，最酷的孩子们得到了最酷的聚会地点：
the staircase.
他们可以在上面，看着我们所有人。
- They get to be up there and look down on all of us.
我想上去，然后俯视我们自己。
- I want to be up there and look down on us.
首先，得让他们承认我们的存在。
- First we have to get them to acknowledge that we exist.
让我来搞定这个。
- Let me handle this.
- 我来处理这件事。
- Okay, you know what to do, right? - Yes. - Don't mess up!
- 好的，你知道该怎么做，对吧？ - 是的。 - 别搞砸了！
- 'Sup.
- 最近怎么样？
[squealing quietly]
[轻声尖叫]
- Did you hear that?
- 你听到了吗？
They 'sup-ed us back!
他们回应我们了！
- What should we do now? Send them a thank you note?
- 我们现在该怎么办？给他们发个感谢信？
- No, that 'sup went great.
- 不，那个回应很棒。
All we got to do is just play it cool,
我们只需要保持冷静，
and we'll be getting an invite to the stairs any day now...
我们很快就会收到去楼梯间的邀请...
As long as one of us doesn't do anything embarrassing.
只要我们中没有人做出什么尴尬的事情。
- Hey, guys, check out Dad's old stuff I found in the attic!
- 嘿，伙计们，看看我在阁楼上找到的爸爸的旧东西！
I'm gonna wear it at school tomorrow!
我明天要穿着它去学校！
- [sighs]
- [叹气]
Is he one of us?
他是我们中的一员吗？
- Yes.
- 是的。
Yes, he is.
是的，他是。
[upbeat music]
[欢快音乐]
- ♪ Na, na, na, na, na, na, na, na, na, na, na ♪ - ♪ Hey! ♪
- ♪ 呐，呐，呐，呐，呐，呐，呐，呐，呐，呐 ♪ - ♪ 嘿！ ♪
♪ Na, na, na, na, na, na, na, na, na, na, na, ♪
♪ 呐，呐，呐，呐，呐，呐，呐，呐，呐，呐，呐 ♪
[whistling]
口哨声
♪ ♪
- ♪ One, two, three, four! ♪
- ♪ 一，二，三，四！ ♪
♪ ♪
- ♪ Na, na, na, na, na, na ♪
- ♪ 呐，呐，呐，呐，呐，呐 ♪
♪ Na, na, na, na, na, na ♪ - ♪ Hey! ♪
♪ 呐，呐，呐，呐，呐，呐 ♪ - ♪ 嘿！ ♪
♪ One, two ♪ - ♪ Na, na, na, na, na, na ♪
♪ 一，二 ♪ - ♪ 呐，呐，呐，呐，呐，呐 ♪
- ♪ One, two, three, four! ♪
- ♪ 一，二，三，四！ ♪
- ♪ Na, na, na, na, na, na, na, na, na, na, na ♪
- ♪ 呐，呐，呐，呐，呐，呐，呐，呐，呐，呐 ♪
- [grunts]
- [咕哝声]
This stupid zipper's lost its zip.
这愚蠢的拉链失去了它的拉力。
Come on.
快点。
- Ricky, come down!
- 里基，下来！
We're making ice cream sundaes!
我们在做冰淇淋圣代！
- Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa. Ice cream sundaes?
- 哇，哇，哇，哇，哇。冰淇淋圣代？
I'm in.
我加入。
- Sorry, Mom.
- 对不起，妈妈。
It's a quad thing, and there's only four bowls.
这是四人组的事，而且只有四个碗。
- Aw.
- 哎。
Fine.
好吧。
Mmm.
嗯。
Look who is dressed for success! You look adorable, honey. - Thanks, Mom.
瞧谁打扮得这么成功！你看起来真可爱，亲爱的。
- Hey, hey, hey,
谢谢，妈妈。
see if you can hook a mother up with some moose tracks.
嘿，嘿，嘿，
Great.
看看你能不能给老妈来点麋鹿轨迹冰淇淋。
- Normally, I'm a two-scoop guy,
太好了。
but I think I'm gonna make a "brief case" for three scoops.
通常我只吃两球，
What's going on? - Have a seat.
但我想我这次要为三球找个“理由”。
- Where's the sundaes? - There are no sundaes.
发生什么事了？
- Well, maybe after. - There will be no sundaes. - What if it goes well?
- 也许之后吧。 - 不会有圣代的。 - 如果一切顺利呢？
- Look, we don't have any ice cream.
- 看，我们没有冰淇淋。
- What is going on here?
- 这里到底发生了什么？
- Yeah, what is going on here?
- 是啊，这里到底发生了什么？
- Look, you're our brother, and we care about you.
- 看，你是我们的兄弟，我们关心你。
That's why we're going to tell you this
- 这就是为什么我们要尽可能委婉地告诉你这件事。
as delicately as possible.
- 丢掉公文包，呆子。
- Lose the briefcase, dork.
- 迪基，那可不委婉。
- Dicky, that's not delicate.
- 哦，对。
- Oh, right.
- 还有遮阳帽和背带...呆子。
The visor and suspenders too...
还有遮阳帽和背带...
dork.
呆子。
- But Mom said I look adorable,
- 但是妈妈说我看起来很可爱，
so it's Mom-approved.
所以是妈妈批准的。
- You mean, this Mom?
- 你是说，这个妈妈？
- Oh, problem with zipper on fanny pack!
- 哦，腰包的拉链有问题！
Fanny pack!
腰包！
[sighs]
[叹气]
Representative!
代表！
- I don't know what you guys are so concerned about.
- 我不知道你们在担心什么。
This stuff all serves a purpose.
这些东西都有其用途。
The visor reduces glare and protects my eyes.
遮阳板减少眩光，保护我的眼睛。
The suspenders hold up my pants,
背带支撑着我的裤子，
as well as my studious image,
也支撑着我勤奋的形象，
and this baby...
而这个宝贝...
takes organization to a whole new level.
将组织能力提升到了一个全新的水平。
- You mean "dork-inzation."
你是说“书呆子化”吧。
The kids at school are ruthless.
学校里的孩子们可是毫不留情的。
Remember what happened to Marshall?
还记得马歇尔发生了什么事吗？
- Who? - Exactly.
谁？ - 没错。
- Whoa!
哇！
Marshall, are those ducks on your socks?
Marshall，你袜子上是鸭子吗？
Quack, quack!
嘎，嘎！
[laughter]
[笑声]
From now on, you're Duck Sock Boy.
从现在开始，你就是鸭袜男孩了。
Quack, quack!
嘎，嘎！
- But I don't want to be Duck Sock Boy!
但我不想当鸭袜男孩！
- Don't worry, Marshall.
别担心，Marshall。
A nickname only sticks if two people say it.
只有两个人说出口，昵称才会粘住。
- Thanks, Mae.
谢谢，Mae。
- What's up, Duck Sock Boy?
- 怎么了，鸭袜男孩？
- Tough break, Duck Sock Boy.
- 真倒霉，鸭袜男孩。
- Duck Sock Boy's real name is Marshall?
- 鸭袜男孩的真名是马歇尔？
- Yup.
- 是的。
And rumor has it the staircase kids were so close
而且有传言说楼梯孩子们差点
to inviting him onto the steps.
就邀请他加入他们的行列了。
- He could have been somebody.
- 他本可以成为某个人的。
- Guys, I don't care about nicknames or the staircase kids.
- 伙计们，我不在乎什么绰号或者楼梯孩子们。
I'm interested in climbing the ladder of success,
我感兴趣的是攀登成功之梯，
not the staircase of popularity.
而不是人气之梯。
So I thank you for your concern,
所以我感谢你的关心，
but these are gonna take me to the top.
但这些会带我到达顶峰。
- Well, you got to hand it to him; he doesn't care what other people think.
- 好吧，你得承认他；他不在乎别人怎么想。
- But we do!
- 但我们在乎！
I'm telling you, if we let our brother
我告诉你，如果我们让我们的哥哥
show up to school like that,
那样去学校，
we can kiss the staircase good-bye.
我们就可以和楼梯说再见了。
- We can't let that happen.
- 我们不能让这种事发生。
- Which is why we're going to wait until Ricky's asleep
- 这就是为什么我们要等到里基睡着了
and then steal all of his goober gear.
然后偷走他所有的怪装备。
- Guess who just complained her way into a new fanny pack?
猜猜谁刚刚抱怨着得到了一个新的腰包？
- We got to steal Mom's goober gear too.
我们还得偷妈妈的怪异装备。
♪ ♪
- [snoring]
[打呼噜]
- Okay, he's snoring. Let's move.
好了，他在打呼噜。我们行动吧。
- Wait, he's not in a deep sleep yet.
等等，他还没进入深度睡眠。
- How do we know when he's in a deep sleep?
我们怎么知道他进入深度睡眠了？
- He sleep rhymes.
他会说梦话押韵。
- Sleep rhymes?
说梦话押韵？
- I am handsome, smart, and funny.
我英俊、聪明又幽默。
When I grow up,
当我长大后，
I'll make lots of money.
我会赚很多钱。
- Wow.
哇。
Okay, you find the suspenders.
好吧，你找背带。
You find the visor.
你找帽舌。
I'll find the briefcase. Let's move!
我找公文包。我们行动吧！
[suspenseful music]
[悬疑音乐]
- Ow!
哎哟！
♪ ♪
- Guys!
伙计们！
Okay, now we just have to find the briefcase.
好的，现在我们只需要找到那个公文包。
Where would he hide it?
他会把它藏在哪里呢？
- My briefcase will make me the best.
- 我的公文包会让我成为最好的。
That's why I hug it while I rest.
这就是为什么我在休息时紧紧抱着它。
- Let's roll!
- 我们走吧！
♪ ♪
- Guys!
- 伙计们！
♪ ♪
Okay, on three I'm going to change it out with a pillow.
好的，三声之后我会用枕头替换它。
- All right.
- 好的。
- One, two--
一、二——
- Mom's three bean chili was off the chart,
妈妈的三豆辣椒真是太棒了，
but now I really have to...
但现在我真的得……
start eating better.
开始吃得健康些。
- Three!
三！
♪ ♪
[alarm clock rings]
[闹钟响]
- Good morning, Mr. Briefcase!
早上好，公文包先生！
[gasps]
[倒抽一口气]
Nooo!
不！
- Okay, he's up. You hid all of his stuff, right?
好的，他起来了。你把他所有的东西都藏好了，对吧？
- Oh, yes, in a place he'll never look in a million years.
哦，是的，藏在一个他一百万年也不会去看的地方。
- Good. Oh, and remember:
很好。哦，还有记得：
look innocent.
看起来要无辜。
- Okay, where are they?
好的，东西在哪儿？
- We have no idea what you are talking about.
我们完全不知道你在说什么。
- Muffin? - Don't "muffin" me.
小松饼？
I know you hid my stuff somewhere,
别“小松饼”我。
and I'm gonna get it out of you.
我知道你把我的东西藏在某个地方，
The truth is in your eyes.
我会从你嘴里撬出来的。
- [gagging, coughing]
- [被噎住，咳嗽]
- Sorry, I didn't brush my teeth yet.
- 对不起，我还没刷牙。
Your eyes aren't telling me anything.
你的眼睛什么也没告诉我。
Your eyes aren't telling me anything either.
你的眼睛也没告诉我什么。
- No, but they are watering.
- 不，但它们在流泪。
- I hope my eyes aren't telling you
- 我希望我的眼睛没告诉你
that I hid them in the freezer.
我把它们藏在冰箱里了。
- Aha!
- 啊哈！
- Aw, that is bad.
- 哦，那可不好。
- Please tell me you didn't hide them in the freezer
- 请告诉我你没把它们藏在冰箱里
just because you thought that would make them "cooler."
只是因为你觉得那样会让它们“更酷”。
- I won't, but apparently my eyes
- 我不会，但显然我的眼睛
won't keep their mouth shut.
不会保持沉默。
- The next time you see this stuff
- 下次你再看到这些东西
will be when I'm wearing them at school.
将会是我戴着它们去学校的时候。
- At least Mom will never find her fanny pack.
- 至少妈妈永远不会找到她的腰包。
- What was this doing in my sock drawer?
- 这东西怎么会在我的袜子抽屉里？
- I've never seen her wear socks.
- 我从来没见过她穿袜子。
♪ ♪
- Okay, good, nobody's here yet.
- 好吧，很好，还没人来。
Let's move.
我们走吧。
- I'm telling you, you're overreacting.
我跟你说，你反应过度了。
I don't need a wall in front of me.
我不需要墙挡在我前面。
- Hey, guys.
嘿，伙计们。
Why y'all hall-walling?
你们为什么在走廊里挡着？
- Because of this.
因为这。
- We're gonna need a bigger wall.
我们需要一堵更大的墙。
- Hey! - Hey.
嘿！
- Hi.
嘿。
- I don't need a wall.
我不需要墙。
- Ricky, we're doing this for you.
Ricky，我们这么做都是为了你。
- Yeah, if you don't look good,
是啊，如果你看起来不好，
we don't look good.
我们看起来也不好。
- Oh, so you're doing this for you.
哦，这么说你们是为了自己。
- How could you even ask that?
你怎么会问这种问题？
Of course we're doing it for us!
当然是为了我们自己！
We are this close to being on the staircase.
我们离楼梯就差那么一点点了。
- Well, in that case, these are definitely not coming off.
好吧，那样的话，这些绝对不能脱掉。
Ouch.
哎哟。
- Fine, that's it.
好吧，就这样。
You leave us no choice.
你们没给我们选择余地。
Boys, it's go time.
伙计们，是时候行动了。
- Oh, no, no, no, no, no.
哦，不，不，不，不，不。
- Now do you see what you look like?
现在你看到自己像什么样子了吗？
- Oh, I'm sorry.
哦，对不起。
Am I supposed to dress like this?
我应该这样打扮吗？
- Oh, no, no, no, no, no!
哦，不，不，不，不，不！
- Everyone, look at me!
大家，看我！
I'm wearing sunglasses inside, 'cause that makes sense!
我在室内戴太阳镜，因为这有道理！
- My suspend-dorks keep my smarty pants up!
我的吊带裤让我的聪明裤子不掉！
- I'm wearing half a hat and it makes my face look green.
- 我只戴了半个帽子，结果脸都绿了。
- I've got a beef case for all my important meat.
- 我有个装牛肉的箱子，装我所有重要的肉。
- It's a briefcase for meetings.
- 这是会议用的公文包。
- Hey, check it out!
- 嘿，看这个！
It's Suspender Girl, Visor Boy, and Briefcase Man.
这是吊带裤女孩、遮阳帽男孩和公文包男。
- Don't worry, guys.
- 别担心，伙计们。
A nickname only sticks if two people say it.
绰号只有两个人说才会粘住。
- Suspender Girl, Visor Boy, Briefcase Man!
- 吊带裤女孩，遮阳帽男孩，公文包男！
[together in slow motion] Nooo!
[慢动作齐声] 不！
- Whoa, you were right.
- 哇，你说得对。
This could have ruined me.
这本可能毁了我。
Thanks, Suspender Girl, Visor Boy, and Briefcase Man.
谢谢，吊带女孩，遮阳帽男孩，公文包男人。
[laughter]
[笑声]
- ♪ Oh-oh-ooh oh-ooh-oh-ohh ♪
♪ 哦-哦-哦 哦-哦-哦-哦 ♪
♪ ♪
- Now they'll never invite us onto the stairs.
现在他们永远不会邀请我们上楼梯了。
- Hold on, everybody.
等等，大家。
I know it's been said twice and everything,
我知道这已经说过两次了，
but this is not what we look like.
但这不是我们的样子。
You see us every day.
你每天都看到我们。
You even 'sup-ed us yesterday.
你昨天还和我们一起吃饭了。
You know we don't dress like this.
你知道我们不会穿成这样的。
Tell them, Mae.
告诉他们，Mae。
- They don't.
他们不会。
- So you're sticking up for them now, huh?
所以你现在是在为他们辩护了，嗯？
Well, maybe we should call you The Suspender Defender.
好吧，也许我们应该叫你‘吊带保卫者’。
- Oh, no, that's once!
哦，不，就这一次！
Uh...
呃...
[imitating PA system] Mae Valentine,
（模仿广播系统）Mae Valentine，
please report to the office.
请到办公室报到。
Got to go!
得走了！
- Fine.
好吧。
Ricky, you defend the suspenders.
Ricky，你来为背带辩护。
They're yours.
它们是你的。
- Please, you expect us to believe that?
拜托，你指望我们相信这个？
Look at this guy.
看看这家伙。
The untucked shirt, flat bill hat,
没塞进裤子的衬衫，平顶帽，
the drop-crotch pants.
低裆裤。
- Usually we like a lower drop.
通常我们喜欢更低一点的裆。
- Yeah, but he still has his headphones plugged into nothing.
是啊，但他耳机还是插在什么都没有的地方。
I trust this guy.
我相信这家伙。
Ricky, from now on, we're gonna call you "the R-Man."
里奇，从现在开始，我们叫你“R侠”。
- Did you hear that? I'm the R-Man!
- 你听到了吗？我是R侠！
- It's not official.
- 这还不是正式的。
It hasn't been said twice.
还没被说两次。
- R-Man... - That's twice!
- R侠... - 这已经是第二次了！
- Hey, R-Man, you got a sec?
- 嘿，R侠，你有空吗？
Not you, Arman.
不是你，阿尔曼。
You.
是你。
- You've got to straighten this out. They trust you.
- 你得把这事摆平。他们信任你。
Tell them we're not really Suspender Girl,
告诉他们我们其实不是吊带女孩、护目镜男孩和公文包男人。
Visor Boy, and Briefcase man.
我应该对你生气……
- I should be mad at you...
但R侠不记仇，
but the R-Man doesn't hold grudges,
所以我会看看能做些什么。
so I'll see what I can do.
R侠。
- The R-Man.
他们不该叫他R侠。
They shouldn't be calling him the R-Man.
他们应该叫我R侠！
They should be calling me the R-Man!
你的名字以D开头。
- Your name starts with a D. - I think you're missing the point.
我觉得你没抓住重点。
- Let's just hope the R-Man works his magic.
我们只能希望R侠施展他的魔法。
- Just watch me. - Not you!
- 就看我的吧。 - 不是你！
- Hey, guys, great news.
- 嘿，伙计们，好消息。
- They don't care about our new, stupid nicknames?
- 他们不在乎我们这些新起的傻绰号吗？
- Oh, no, they definitely care about those.
- 哦，不，他们绝对在乎那些。
I meant great news for me.
我是说对我来说是好消息。
They invited me to hang out with them.
他们邀请我一起玩了。
- On the staircase? - Second step.
- 在楼梯上？ - 第二级台阶。
- Second step already? That's unprecedented!
- 第二级台阶？这可是破天荒的！
- But they know you're related to us!
- 但他们知道你跟我们是一伙的！
Why didn't our stink get on you
为什么我们的臭味没沾到你身上
the way your stink was gonna get on us?
你的臭味会沾到我们身上？
- You know what?
- 你知道吗？
We talked about the related thing,
我们谈过那个亲戚的事，
and they're fine with it.
他们对此没问题。
So I guess you guys were worried about nothing.
所以我想你们是白担心了。
You live; you learn.
生活就是边活边学。
R-Man out!
R-Man 出去了！
- Not you!
- 不是你！
♪ ♪
- ♪ Na, na, na, na, na, na, na, na, na, na, na ♪
♪ Na, na, na, na, na, na, na, na, na, na ♪
[sewing machine whirring]
[缝纫机嗡嗡声]
- Looks like the R-Man's doing a little stress sewing.
- 看来R-Man正在做些缓解压力的缝纫活。
- I knit for stress.
- 我通过编织来缓解压力。
I sew for success.
我通过缝纫来追求成功。
I'm dropping the crotch on my pants.
我正在给我的裤子缝裆部。
That's how we roll up there on the stairs.
这就是我们在楼梯上滚动的风格。
- Since when do you roll?
- 你什么时候开始滚动的？
- Since I got in with the popular kids.
- 自从我和那些受欢迎的孩子混在一起后。
- Since when do you care about popularity?
- 你什么时候开始在乎人气的？
- About the time I started rolling.
- 大约是我开始滚动的时候。
- I thought all you cared about was the "ladder of success"?
- 我以为你只在乎“成功阶梯”呢？
- That's when I was on the ground like you.
- 那是我像你一样在地上的时候。
You should see the view from up there.
你应该看看那上面的风景。
You never will, but you should!
你永远不会看到，但你应该看看！
- Ricky, look what you're doing.
- 里基，看看你在做什么。
You're dropping the crotch on your pants just to be popular.
你为了受欢迎，连裤裆都往下拉。
This isn't you.
这不是你。
It's us!
是我们！
- Yeah, we're the cool ones!
- 没错，我们才是酷的那群人！
- Well, my trouser trench begs to differ.
- 好吧，我的裤缝可不同意。
- Hey, kids.
嘿，孩子们。
Hey, nice hemming stitch, honey.
嘿，亲爱的，缝边针脚不错。
- Actually, it's a zigzag stitch.
实际上，这是锯齿形针脚。
- Ooh! Tell me more.
哦！再多告诉我一些。
- I don't think we have to worry.
我觉得我们不必担心。
He's gonna zigzag his way right off those stairs.
他会像锯齿一样从楼梯上滑下去的。
- Zigzag stitch?
锯齿形针脚？
Nice call, R-Man.
好样的，R-Man。
- What is happening?
发生了什么？
- Those are pretty low.
那些真的很低。
What do you think, Trey?
你觉得呢，特雷？
Are they fifth-step low?
他们是第五级台阶低吗？
- No...
不...
they're sixth-step low!
是第六级台阶低！
[all gasp]
[所有人都倒吸一口气]
- Whoa, this view is a knee-buckler.
哇，这个景色真是让人膝盖发软。
Ooh!
哦！
Thank you!
谢谢！
It's good to be on step six.
站在第六级台阶上感觉真好。
- Step six gets chocolate cake?
第六级台阶有巧克力蛋糕吗？
- He's having our cake.
- And eating it too!
[bell rings]
- Well, at least we're not
wearing Ricky's goober gear today.
Maybe people won't even remember.
- Hey, what's up Visor Boy,
Suspender Girl, and Briefcase Boy?
- It's Briefcase Man.
If you're gonna say it, say it right.
- How are we gonna get to class
- 我们怎么才能在最少人看到的情况下到达教室？
with the least amount of people seeing us?
- 你可以总是走...
- You could always go down...
- 另一条走廊。
the other hallway.
[所有人都惊讶地吸气]
[all gasp]
- 一定有别的办法！
- There has to be another way!
- 别担心，不会那么糟糕的。
- Don't worry, it can't be that bad.
- 那么，你会和我们一起去吗？
- Well, will you go with us?
- 呃...
- Uh...
[模仿PA系统] Mae Valentine，
[imitating PA system] Mae Valentine,
请到校长办公室报到。
please report to the principal's office.
请到校长室报告。
What have I done this time?
这次我又做了什么？
- ♪ Oh-oh-ooh-oh ♪
♪哦-哦-哦-哦♪
♪ Oh-oh-ooh oh-ooh-oh-ohh ♪
♪哦-哦-哦-哦-哦♪
[water dripping, lights clicking]
[水滴声，灯光开关声]
- Agh! - Ah, ghost!
啊！- 啊，鬼！
- It's a pigeon!
是鸽子！
- Ghost pigeon!
幽灵鸽子！
boy: Hello, Harpers.
男孩：你好，哈珀一家。
children: Harpers, Harpers, Harpers.
孩子们：哈珀一家，哈珀一家，哈珀一家。
- Who is that?
- 那是谁？
- Show yourself!
- 现身吧！
Duck Sock Boy?
鸭袜男孩？
- Welcome to The Hall of Shame.
- 欢迎来到耻辱堂。
children: Shame, shame, shame.
孩子们: 耻辱，耻辱，耻辱。
- Wow, this place has quite an echo...
- 哇，这个地方回声真大...
- No, those are just the other kids with unfortunate nicknames.
- 不，那只是其他有着不幸昵称的孩子。
all: Nicknames, nicknames, nicknames.
所有人: 昵称，昵称，昵称。
- Okay, they get it, guys.
- 好了，他们明白了，伙计们。
all: Sorry, sorry, sorry.
所有人: 对不起，对不起，对不起。
- It's not that bad down here.
这里下面其实没那么糟糕。
You three are going to fit right in.
你们三个会很快适应的。
See you tomorrow
明天见
and every day until we graduate.
还有每天直到我们毕业。
- Guys, we can't live like this.
伙计们，我们不能这样生活。
We have to do something.
我们必须做点什么。
- Something, something, something.
做点什么，做点什么，做点什么。
Hey, that is kind of fun!
嘿，这还挺有趣的！
- Seriously!
说真的！
There's only one way out of here.
离开这里只有一条路。
- Back the way we came?
- 原路返回？
- Okay, two.
- 好的，两条。
- What about that staircase right there?
- 那边的楼梯怎么样？
- Okay, fine, there are a lot of ways to get out of here!
- 好吧，好吧，有很多方法可以离开这里！
But only one way will make sure
但只有一种方法能确保
that we never have to use this hallway again.
我们再也不必使用这条走廊。
- Okay, how's the crotch on these?
- 好吧，这些裤裆怎么样？
all: Lower!
所有人: 低一点！
- Okay.
- 好的。
[in a deep voice] How's the crotch on these?
[用低沉的声音] 这些裤裆怎么样？
[laughs]
[笑]
♪
- All right, what's the plan again?
- 好吧，计划是什么来着？
- Strut, stop, 'sup.
- 大步走，停下，怎么了。
- Got it.
- 明白了。
Strut, strut, strut.
大步走，大步走，大步走。
- You don't need to say "strut."
- 你不需要说“大步走”。
Now stop.
现在停下。
Stop saying "strut," not stop strutting!
停下说“大步走”，不是停下大步走！
Strut!
大步走！
'Sup.
嗨。
- [whispering] We didn't get a 'sup.
- [低语] 我们没听到‘嗨’。
- So what do you think of our pants?
- 那你觉得我们的裤子怎么样？
Pretty low, huh?
很低，对吧？
- Low?
- 低？
[laughs]
[笑]
- The R-Man's sweeping the floor with his.
- R侠用他的裤子扫地。
- Whoa. That is low.
- 哇。那确实很低。
- The R-Man set a school record.
- R侠创下了学校纪录。
- Okay, that is it!
- 好了，就这样！
This is ridiculous!
这太荒谬了！
He's not the R-Man, he's Ricky Harper!
他不是R-Man，他是Ricky Harper！
And he's not cool; he irons!
而且他并不酷；他还在熨衣服！
- That's cool. - His belt!
- 那很酷。 - 他的腰带！
- I hate a wrinkled belt.
- 我讨厌皱巴巴的腰带。
- Okay, how about this?
- 好吧，这个怎么样？
He's in the Calculator of the Month club.
他是月度计算器俱乐部的成员。
- I know.
- 我知道。
He gave me October.
他给了我十月份的。
Thanks, R-Man.
谢谢，R-Man。
- Okay, how about this one?
- 好吧，这个怎么样？
Ricky sleep-rhymes.
Ricky 睡觉时押韵。
- Sleep-what?
- 睡觉时什么？
- Rhymes.
- 押韵。
[all gasp]
[大家都惊讶]
- R-Man, is this true?
- R-Man，这是真的吗？
'Cause if it is,
因为如果是真的，
then that is not cool!
那就不酷了！
- Yeah, according to my calculations,
- 是的，根据我的计算，
that equals...
那等于...
seven...
七...
which is lame.
这很逊。
- They're not sleep rhymes...
- 它们不是催眠诗...
they're...
它们是...
sleep raps.
催眠说唱。
I dabble in the art of hip-hop.
我在嘻哈艺术方面有所涉猎。
- Oh, really?
- 哦，真的吗？
- Why don't you rap for us right now?
- 那你为什么不现在给我们来一段说唱？
- Oh, I would,
- 哦，我会的，
but...
但是...
I don't have a beat or anything.
我没有节奏或任何东西。
[hip-hop beat]
[嘻哈节奏]
There's not really any room out here for me to perform.
这里真的没有空间让我表演。
- Well, then why don't you go to the top step,
- 那么，你为什么不走到最上面的台阶，
where there's plenty of room?
那里有很多空间？
- Oh, but I don't have top-step access.
- 哦，但我没有上到最上面台阶的权限。
- Actually, with those floor-sweepers, you do.
- 实际上，有了那些扫地机，你就可以。
♪ ♪
- R-Man, R-Man, R-Man, R-Man!
Not you, Arman.
不是你，Arman。
R-Man, R-Man!
all: R-Man, R-Man, R-Man, R-Man!
大家: R-Man, R-Man, R-Man, R-Man!
- This is ridiculous!
- 这太荒谬了！
I don't even have a mic!
- 我连麦克风都没有！
♪ ♪
Of course.
当然。
♪ ♪
♪ Yo, yo, my name is R-Man and I'm here to say ♪
♪ 哟，哟，我的名字是R-Man，我来这里要说 ♪
♪ Brush your teeth not once, but twice a day ♪
♪ 刷牙不是一次，而是每天两次 ♪
- Is he really rapping about brushing his teeth?
- 他真的在唱关于刷牙的歌吗？
- Wait.
等等。
I want to see where this goes.
我想看看这会发展到什么地步。
- ♪ And don't y'all forget that you got to floss too ♪
别忘了你们还得用牙线。
♪ It helps get rid of the food you eat ♪
它有助于清除你吃的食物。
♪ I mean, chew ♪
我的意思是，咀嚼。
♪ Like a kangaroo ♪
像袋鼠一样。
♪ A cow goes moo ♪
牛会哞哞叫。
- This is not going to a good place.
这不会发展到好地方。
all: Boo!
嘘！
♪ ♪
Off the stairs! Off the stairs!
下楼梯！下楼梯！
Off the stairs!
下楼梯！
Off the stairs! Off the stairs!
下楼梯！下楼梯！
- Poor Ricky.
可怜的Ricky。
- I thought this would make me feel better,
我以为这会让我感觉好些，
but now I feel worse.
但现在我感觉更糟了。
We got to save him.
我们得救他。
- Let's do this.
我们开始吧。
- Hey, you don't have top-step access!
嘿，你没有最高台阶的权限！
[hip-hop beat]
[嘻哈节奏]
♪ ♪
- ♪ Listen up, y'all, I mean the whole school ♪
听着，各位，我是说整个学校
♪ If you laugh at Ricky, then you be the fool ♪
如果你嘲笑Ricky，那你就是个傻瓜
♪ This whole thing started 'cause we wanted on the stairs ♪
这一切都始于我们想上楼梯
♪ When we really should have thought, "You know what, who cares?" ♪ - both: Word!
当我们真的应该想，“你知道吗，谁在乎呢？”
♪ ♪
- ♪ So what if we look stupid ♪
所以如果我们看起来很蠢
♪ 'Cause we wore some silly clothes? ♪
因为我们穿了些傻傻的衣服？
♪ It's not the name you're nicked ♪
这不是你的名字被取笑
♪ It's who you are down to your toes ♪ - both: Word!
而是你从脚到头的本质
- ♪ Unique is what we are, so don't be dumb, be proud ♪
独特是我们的标签，所以不要犯傻，要自豪
♪ Don't hide yourself, pride yourself ♪
不要隐藏自己，要为自己骄傲
♪ And yell it clear and loud ♪
并大声清晰地喊出来
Mo' nicknames, mo' problems.
更多的绰号，更多的问题
Boom!
砰！
[cheers and applause]
（欢呼和掌声）
- Hey, guys, thanks for sticking up for me.
嘿，伙计们，谢谢你们支持我
Up top!
击掌！
[all grunting]
（所有人发出咕噜声）
- ♪ That fall down the stairs, it wasn't no joke ♪
那次从楼梯上摔下来，可不是开玩笑的
♪ I just hope my arm didn't... broke ♪
♪我只希望我的手臂♪ ♪没...断♪
all: Word!
说得好！
- At least we're on the stairs.
- 至少我们在楼梯上。
- Get off the stairs.
- 离开楼梯。
- Oh, sorry.
- 哦，对不起。
♪
[whistling]
[吹口哨]
♪ ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ 耶，耶，耶，♪ ♪耶，耶♪
♪ 耶，耶，♪ ♪耶，耶，耶♪
- ♪ Yeah! ♪
♪ 耶！ ♪
- ♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ 耶，耶，耶，耶，耶 ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ 耶，耶，耶，耶 ♪
- ♪ Yeah! ♪
♪ 耶！ ♪